ARAM PODOLSKI

PROFILE

I am a software engineer based in Denver, Colorado. I am comfortable with back-end, front-end and all things AWS. I am the co-creator of Haven, a centralized secrets manager for small teams. Previously, I worked as a flight software engineer for the Orion space program.

EXPERIENCE

2020 - present

Haven, Co-Creator, Software Engineer

haven-secrets.github.io ∂

- Co-created open-source secrets manager using AWS, Node.js, Express and React/Redux.
- Implemented secrets storage in AWS using DynamoDB to minimize latency.
- Resolved issue of temporary credentials by utilizing AWS Lambda to enforce one hour limit for new user creation.
- Utilized AWS CloudFormation to ensure architecture is set up and torn down in a repeatable manner.
- Set up AWS IAM permissions to restrict access to AWS KMS master key and secrets on a per project and environment basis.
- Designed solution utilizing AWS Encryption SDK to perform envelope encryption of application secrets.
- Designed user-friendly UI in React and CLI to allow users to easily centralize their secrets.
- Co-authored technical case study: https://haven-secrets.github.io/case-study ∂

2020 - present

Self-Employed, Full-stack Web Developer

Built large number of full-stack web applications including:

- A React web application that allows for viewing and filtering of airline routes.
- A ticket tracking application built using Ruby/Rails and PostgreSQL.
- A Trello-like application with Rails REST API back-end and React/Redux front-end.

2014 - 2020

ISYS Technologies, Software Engineer, Senior Software Engineer

- Worked on the flight software team for the Orion Multi-Purpose Crew Vehicle.
 Duties included software preliminary design, detailed design, coding, testing, integration, verification and build management.
- Developed mission critical software to route commands from the Crew Module to appropriate component on European Service Module for Artmeis I.
- Updated software and documentation based on feedback from NASA stakeholders.

EDUCATION

2009 - 2013

B.S. Aerospace Engineering, University of Colorado at Boulder

SKILLS

Back End

Ruby, PostgreSQL, Express, Rails **Front End**

Javascript(ES6), React, Redux, CSS, HTML Cloud(AWS)

Lambda, KMS, DynamoDB, CloudFormation, SDK, IAM Other

Git, Perforce, Jira, Confluence, Crucible, REST APIs, C++